TIMOTHY LEE

Austin, TX

P: 330.219.4348

E: timothy.d.lee@live.com

G: https://github.com/timothydlee



Objective

I am seeking a junior web development position leveraging my full stack skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL, PHP, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Firebase, Handlebars, Sequelize and MongoDB.

Summary

I am a junior developer who has a passion for learning and documented a history of success in all my previous work experiences. I began my professional life as a temporary employee of a Fortune 500 Oil & Gas company and within five years, I had been promoted into the company's Chief Intellectual Property Counsel's personal team of five.

Work Experience

Kellogg Brown & Root

Houston, TX — 2011-2016

Contract Manager, KBR (2015-2016)

I was recruited by and successfully integrated into the legal department as a non-attorney with no legal training. Despite lack of formal training or education in the legal space, the Chief IP Counsel of KBR recognized my tech skills and ability to adapt and transferred me directly into his team of five.

Accomplishments

- Negotiated and executed over 140 non-disclosure agreements (NDAs) while maintaining a database of over 400 NDAs in various stages of negotiation across all business lines.
- Seamlessly transitioned the IP Department's legal process from an email-based one to one utilizing the Salesforce ecosystem to streamline workflow.

Business Development - Technical Services, KBR (2014-2015)

I was recognized for my ability to work well in situations requiring coordination across multiple teams and being a positive face for the company; responsible for the signing of fourteen new technical services agreements and generating over \$4.7 million in job income.

Sales Coordinator, KBR (2011-2014)

Expedited resolution of over 100 international deals in the crude processing and ammonia producing technology spaces ranging in values up to \$55 million, while requiring input from multiple departments including regional sales, business unit and corporate management, ops, international trade compliance, legal, tax, corporate business development oversight and treasury and maintaining an interface with customers.

Education

University of Michigan

BS in Biology with Concentration in Microbiology — 2008-2010

Skills

Advanced in Microsoft Office Suite, Salesforce and Sharepoint.

Skilled in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Firebase, Handlebars, Sequelize and MongoDB.

Interests

Nationals Level Competitive Ultimate Frisbee Player, Soccer Player, Pianist